jasminedirectory.com 2018-08-29

# Jasmine Directory: Submission Guidelines and Privacy Policy

### Simon says...Submission Guidelines

  * In order to keep Jasmine Directory as useful, friendly and safe as possible, we prefer to play safe.

##### Website suggestion related FAQ and guidelines:

  * **Why is Jasmine Directory different?**

The main purpose of Jasmine Directory is to create a user-friendly environment, with a high editorial discretion applied to each and every suggested website, created for those who seek information. We believe this should be the primary motivation for any web directory.

Contrary to the general belief, a web directory should not be just another website allowing a website owner getting a backlink. Such directories violate Google's Guidelines. 

  * **What websites do we add to Jasmine Directory?**

Our editors are adding on a daily basis new listings to our database. Furthermore, other webmasters are allowed to suggest websites to be added to Jasmine Directory by paying a fee, and, if our editors consider that resource useful for others, they'll accept it.

There is a huge difference between "suggesting" a website to a website directory (because a suggestion is subject to approval or rejection) and "a guaranteed listing".

  * **Why can't I suggest websites for free?**

The Internet is huge; there are billions of websites, hundreds of thousands of online businesses. People are mindful about SEO, they read everywhere they need backlinks, they see various metrics like Page Authority or Domain Authority as a divine blessing they must have and so forth.

Basically, a free web directory is spammed with suggestions. DMOZ for example had over 90.000 editors and the review process took years.

So, collecting a modest review fee ensures the quality of our services (hosting and marketing, paying our editors, adding new content and tools etc.) and on the other hand limits the number of suggestions and indirectly reduces web spam.

  * **What kind of websites are added to Jasmine Directory?**

Our primary focus is oriented towards to provide an excellent user experience. Therefore we prefer sites filled with unique information, have decent layout etc.

Before approving a resource (website) we visit that website and decide whether or not that resource (product or service) is useful for users.

  * **What kind of websites are usually rejected?**

Well, it is difficult to name the exact websites we reject. However, we don't accept pharmacy websites (because most of them run illegally), affiliate-only based websites (they don't offer anything unique), redirected websites, websites that sell stolen software, websites which legitimacy is foggy etc.

  * **How should I suggest my website?**

You just need to select a category or subcategory that best describes your website's niche and make use of the "Submit" top menu link.

  * **Can I use whatever website title I want?**

No. We are all fed up with directories listing twenty "Best SEO Company" Guaranteed Results | Click here!!!" in a SEO related category. That is called spam.

Instead, use the official name of your website. We love it, Google loves it!

  * **Okay, what about the description?**

A website's description should not be promotional and shouldn't urge the user to click or buy or call. Also try not to use superlatives like "best", "leading" etc. We want impartiality and objectivity so the user can solely decide where to click. Just imagine a home improvement category filled with ten or twenty "best" businesses offering the same service.

Instead, describe what your website has to offer, what a user can find on your website, specify if you serve only a specific region and so forth.

  * **Why have you edited my listing?**

Making Jasmine Directory a useful resource requires us to exercise a high level of editorial discretion. So, in some cases we may modify the title or the description of the suggested website and/or move it to a more appropriate category.

  * **What's your refund policy?**

We do not offer refunds if the submitter is not pleased with the newly assigned category or the modified title and/or description.

We do not offer refunds after a listing was reviewed, accepted and included in Jasmine Directory.

Submitters should understand that the review fee represents literary just a review fee and not some kind of guarantee or promise.

However, to keep things fair, we refund the review fee if your website will be rejected.

For any active discount codes we reserve the right to refund the discount after 90 days to avoid chargebacks.

  * **Do you remove broken links, parked or dropped domains, suspicious redirects?**

Every 2-3 months we run an entire audit of all our external resources. We don't want to offer our users a bad user experience, so every resource that isn't back online in a resonable time frame will be deleted from Jasmine Directory's database

* * *

To select a suitable category for your website, visit our [homepage](https://www.jasminedirectory.com/) and select a topic based category, check out the [regional section](https://www.jasminedirectory.com/regional/) or browse the alphabetically ordered category list below: 

  * A
  * B
  * C
  * D
  * E
  * F
  * G
  * H
  * I
  * J
  * K
  * L
  * M
  * N
  * O
  * P
  * Q
  * R
  * S
  * T
  * U
  * V
  * W
  * X
  * Y
  * Z

* * *

###  Simon says... Privacy Policy 

  * We have asked you to play save, so we do!

##### Jasmine Directory's Privacy Policy

Jasmine Directory feels strongly that your information and rights must be protected. To this end, we have prepared the following privacy policy to ensure all measures are taken to protect the interests of our visitors and provide a more pleasant site experience.

**What personal information do you collect from the people that visit your website?**

When suggesting a resource to Jasmine Directory, you may be asked to enter your email address in order to be notified about your website's acceptance or rejection.

**When do you collect information?**

We collect information from you when you complete the website submission form successfully.

**How is used the collected information?**

The information collected is used for specific business purposes and is not sold or distributed to any third parties. It is used only for the purposes which the visitor intended: a notification by email when we accept or reject your listing.

**Do you collect any financial information? Like credit card details?**

We DO NOT collect any financial information since all payments are handled by PayPal.

**Do you use "cookies"? Why?**

Yes. We use trusted third-party (Google Analytics) services that track site traffic and site interactions on our behalf.

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information.

**Third-party links**

We list businesses and third-party websites. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

* * *

## **GDPR PRIVACY NOTICE**

**Last updated** May 23, 2018

**INTRODUCTION**

Thank you for choosing to be part of our community at Jasmine Directory (“company”, “we”, “us”, or “our”). We are committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about our policy, or our practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us at support@jasminedirectory.com.

When you visit our website JasmineDirectory.com (“Site”) and use our services, you trust us with your personal information. We take your privacy very seriously. In this privacy notice, we describe our privacy policy. We seek to explain to you in the clearest way possible what information we collect, how we use it and what rights you have in relation to it. We hope you take some time to read through it carefully, as it is important. If there are any terms in this privacy policy that you do not agree with, please discontinue use of our site and our services.

This privacy policy applies to all information collected through our website, https://www.jasminedirectory.com.

**Please read this privacy policy carefully as it will help you make informed decisions about sharing your personal information with us.**

Table of contents

  1. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?
  2. HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?
  3. WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH ANYONE?
  4. DO WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES?
  5. DO WE USE GOOGLE MAPS?
  6. HOW DO WE HANDLE YOUR SOCIAL LOGINS?
  7. IS YOUR INFORMATION TRANSFERRED INTERNATIONALLY?
  8. WHAT IS OUR STANCE ON THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES?
  9. HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?
  10. HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SAFE?
  11. DO WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM MINORS?
  12. WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?
  13. DO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS HAVE SPECIFIC PRIVACY RIGHTS?
  14. DO WE MAKE UPDATES TO THIS POLICY?
  15. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US ABOUT THIS POLICY?

### WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

#### Personal information you disclose to us

**_In Short:_** _We collect personal information that you provide to us such as name, address, contact information, passwords and security data, payment information, and social media login data._

We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when [registering at the Sites or Apps,] expressing an interest in obtaining information about us or our products and services, when participating in activities on the Sites [(such as posting messages in our online forums or entering competitions, contests or giveaways)] or otherwise contacting us.

The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interactions with us and the Sites, the choices you make and the products and features you use. The personal information we collect can include the following:

**Name and Contact Data.** We collect your email address which is necessary to use our services (e.g. receive a confirmation e-mail once your submission is approved, modified or rejected, you forget your password and you request a new one, you contact us for any issue related to our services), and any detail you provide to enhance your listing’s details page. You are fully responsible for the accuracy of the provided data.

**Credentials.** We collect passwords, password hints, and similar security information used for authentication and account access. All these data are encrypted.

**Payment Data**. We DO NOT collect any financial information since all payments are handled by PayPal. However, PayPal, our payment processor (https://www.paypal.com) sends us a confirmation e-mail once you complete a payment.

All personal information that you provide to us must be true, complete and accurate, and you must notify us of any changes to such personal information.

#### Information automatically collected

**_In Short:_** _Some information – such as IP address and/or browser and device characteristics – is collected automatically when you visit our website._

We automatically collect certain information when you visit, use or navigate the Sites. This information does not reveal your specific identity (like your name or contact information) but may include device and usage information, such as your IP address, browser and device characteristics, operating system, language preferences, referring URLs, device name, country, location, information about how and when you use our Site and other technical information. This information is primarily needed to maintain the security and operation of our Sites, and for our internal analytics and reporting purposes.

Like many businesses, we also collect information through cookies and similar technologies. We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site; you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>;

### HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?

**_In Short:_** _We process your information for purposes based on legitimate business interests, the fulfillment of our contract with you, compliance with our legal obligations, and/or your consent._

We use personal information collected via our Sites for a variety of business purposes described below. We process your personal information for these purposes in reliance on our legitimate business interests ("Business Purposes"), in order to enter into or perform a contract with you (“Contractual”), with your consent ("Consent"), and/or for compliance with our legal obligations ("Legal Reasons"). We indicate the specific processing grounds we rely on next to each purpose listed below.

We use the information we collect or receive:

  * To f **ulfill and manage your orders** for Contractual reasons. We may use your information to fulfill and manage your orders, payments, returns, and exchanges made through the Sites.
  * **Administer prize draws and competitions** for our Business Purposes and/or with your Consent. We may use your information to administer prize draws and competitions when you elect to participate in competitions.
  * **Request Feedback** for our Business Purposes and/or with your Consent. We may use your information to request feedback and to contact you about your use of our Sites.
  * **To enable user-to-user communications** with your consent. We may use your information in order to enable user-to-user communications with each user's consent.
  * **To enforce our terms, conditions and policies** for Business Purposes, Legal Reasons and/or possibly Contractual.
  * **To respond to legal requests and prevent harm** for Legal Reasons. If we receive a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data we hold to determine how to respond.
  * **For other Business Purposes**. We may use your information for other Business Purposes, such as data analysis, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and to evaluate and improve our Sites, products, services, marketing and your experience.

**We DO NOT use, under any circumstances, your information to send you promotional content.**

### WILL YOUR INFORMATION BE SHARED WITH ANYONE?

**_In Short:_** _We only share information with your consent, to comply with laws, to protect your rights, or to fulfill business obligations._

We only share and disclose your information in the following situations:

Compliance with Laws. We may disclose your information where we are legally required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, governmental requests, a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).

**Vital Interests and Legal Rights**. We may disclose your information where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding potential violations of our policies, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person and illegal activities, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

**Vendors, Consultants and Other Third-Party Service Providers**. We may share your data with third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform services for us or on our behalf and require access to such information to do that work. Examples

include:

a. payment processing, data analysis, email delivery, hosting services, customer service

and

b. marketing efforts. We may allow selected third parties to use tracking technology on the Sites, which will enable them to collect data about how you interact with the Sites over time. This information may be used to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content and better understand online activity. **Unless described in this Policy, we do not share, sell, rent or trade any of your information with third parties for their promotional purposes.**

**With your Consent.** We may disclose your personal information for any other purpose with your consent.

**Other Users.** When you share personal information (for example, by posting comments, contributions or other content to the Sites) or otherwise interact with public areas of the Site, such personal information may be viewed by all users and may be publicly distributed outside the Site in perpetuity.

### DO WE USE COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES?

**_In Short:_** _We may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect and store your information._

We may use cookies and similar tracking technologies (like web beacons and pixels) to access or store information.

\- "Cookies" are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

\- "Log files" track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.

\- "Web beacons," "tags," and "pixels" are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

### DO WE USE GOOGLE MAPS?

**_In Short:_** _Yes, we use Google Maps for the purpose of providing better service._

This website uses Google Maps APIs. You may find the Google Maps APIs Terms of Service [here](https://developers.google.com/maps/terms). To better understand Google’s Privacy Policy, please refer to this [link](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). By using our Maps API Implementation, you agree to be bound by Google’s Terms of Service. By using our implementation of the Google Maps APIs, you agree to allow us to use information about your website or business location.

For a full list of what we use information for, please see the previous sections titled “Use of Your Information” and “Disclosure of Your Information.”

### IS YOUR INFORMATION TRANSFERRED INTERNATIONALLY?

**_In Short:_** _We may transfer, store, and process your information in countries other than your own._

Our servers are located in the United States of America. If you are accessing our Sites from outside USA, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed by us in our facilities and by those third parties with whom we may share your personal information (see "Disclosure of Your Information" above), in other countries .

If you are a resident in the European Economic Area, then these countries may not have data protection or other laws as comprehensive as those in your country. We will however take all necessary measures to protect your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable law.

In particular GnetAds complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States and has certified its compliance with it. As such, Jasmine Directory is committed to subjecting all personal information received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

GnetAds is responsible for the processing of personal information it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.

With respect to personal information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, GnetAds is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. FTC. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

### WHAT IS OUR STANCE ON THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES?

**_In Short:_** _We are not responsible for the safety of any information that you share with third-party providers who advertise, but are not affiliated with, our websites._

The Sites may contain advertisements from third parties that are not affiliated with us and which may link to other websites, online services or mobile applications. We cannot guarantee the safety and privacy of data you provide to any third parties. Any data collected by third parties is not covered by this privacy policy. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of any third parties, including other websites, services or applications that may be linked to or from the Sites. You should review the policies of such third parties and contact them directly to respond to your questions.

### HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?

**_In Short:_** _We keep your information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy policy unless otherwise required by law. You may ask us anytime to remove your information._

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy unless a longer retention period is required by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). No purpose in this policy will require us keeping your personal information for longer than the period of time in which you have an account with us.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

### HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SAFE?

**_In Short:_** _We aim to protect your personal information through a system of organizational and technical security measures._

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, please also remember that we cannot guarantee that the internet itself is 100% secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, transmission of personal information to and from our Sites is at your own risk. You should only access the services within a secure environment.

DO WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM MINORS?

**_In Short:_** _We do not knowingly collect data from or market to children under 18 years of age._

We do not knowingly solicit data from or market to children under 18 years of age. By using the Sites, you represent that you are at least 18 or that you are the parent or guardian of such a minor and consent to such minor dependent’s use of the Site. If we learn that personal information from users less than 18 years of age has been collected, we will deactivate the account and take reasonable measures to promptly delete such data from our records. If you become aware of any data we have collected from children under age 18, please contact us at info@jasminedirectory.com.

### WHAT ARE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?

**_In Short:_** _In some regions, such as the European Economic Area, you have rights that allow you greater access to and control over your personal information. You may review, change, or terminate your account at any time._

In some regions (like the European Economic Area), you have certain rights under applicable data protection laws. These may include the right (i) to request access and obtain a copy of your personal information, (ii) to request rectification or erasure; (iii) to restrict the processing of your personal information; and (iv) if applicable, to data portability. In certain circumstances, you may also have the right to object to the processing of your personal information. To make such a request, please use the contact details provided below https://www.jasminedirectory.com/contact.html. We will consider and act upon any request in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

If we are relying on your consent to process your personal information, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note however that this will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before its withdrawal.

If you are resident in the European Economic Area and you believe we are unlawfully processing your personal information, you also have the right to complain to your local data protection supervisory authority. You can find their contact details here: http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm

#### Account Information

You may at any time review or change the information in your account or terminate your account by:

  * Contacting us using the contact information provided below

Upon your request to terminate your account, we will deactivate or delete your account and information from our active databases. However, some information may be retained in our files to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use and/or comply with legal requirements.

**_Cookies and similar technologies_** : Most Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our Sites. To opt-out of interest-based advertising by advertisers on our Site visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

**_Opting out of email marketing_** : We do not use your information for any form of email marketing, we will never send you promotional emails – however, we will still need to send you service-related emails that are necessary for the administration and use of your account. You can also opt-out by contacting us using the contact information provided below.

### DO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS HAVE SPECIFIC PRIVACY RIGHTS?

**_In Short:_** _Yes, if you are a resident of California, you are granted specific rights regarding access to your personal information._

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are California residents to request and obtain from us, once a year and free of charge, information about categories of personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to us using the contact information provided below.

If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have a registered account with our Site, you have the right to request removal of unwanted data that you publicly post on the Sites. To request removal of such data, please contact us using the contact information provided below, and include the email address associated with your account and a statement that you reside in California. We will make sure the data is not publicly displayed on the Sites, but please be aware that the data may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems.

### DO WE MAKE UPDATES TO THIS POLICY?

**_In Short:_** _Yes, we will update this policy as necessary to stay compliant with relevant laws._

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. The updated version will be indicated by an updated “Revised” date and the updated version will be effective as soon as it is accessible. If we make material changes to this privacy policy, we may notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to review this privacy policy frequently to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

### HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US ABOUT THIS POLICY?

If you have questions or comments about this policy, email Emily Gilbert at emily.g@jasminedirectory.com or by post to:

GnetAds  
616 Corporate Way, Suite 2-5486  
Valley Cottage, NY 10989

If you are a resident in the European Economic Area, the "data controller" of your personal information is GnetAds LTD. which has appointed Ferenc Ianos to be its representative in the EEA. You can contact them directly regarding the processing of your information by email at [ianos.f@jasminedirectory.com](mailto:ianos.f@jasminedirectory.com).

If you have any further questions or comments about us or our policies, email us at [support@jasminedirectory.com](mailto:support@jasminedirectory.com) or contact us by post at:

GnetAds  
616 Corporate Way, Suite 2-5486  
Valley Cottage, NY 10989
